Guide to the New-York Historical Society Library Department Records 1815-2018 NYHS-RG 21
New-York Historical Society
- Series VIII. Department of Prints, Photographs and Architecture (PPAC, a/k/a Print Room), 1940-2018 (bulk, 1970s-2013); 32.17 Linear feet
  - Subseries VIII.D. Collection Files, 1940-
    - Mixed Material Collections A-Ge (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 1)
      Cruikshank Collection of NYC Views (No PR) [1 folder]
      Delano, William Adams (PR 244) [1 folder]
      Dorsey (PR 17) [1 folder]
      Draper, Ruth (PR 245) [1 folder]
      Ephemera File (PR 264) [1 folder]
      Oscar Fabres (PR 79) [1 folder]
      Geographic File (PR 20) [8 folders]
    - Mixed Material Collections Gi-R (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 2)
      Richard Gilbert Advertising (PR 309) [1 folder]
      Graff, Washbourne & Dunn Silversmiths (PR 243) [1 folder]
      Hamilton, Alexander Morgan, Family Collection (PR 103) [1 folder]
      Hudson-Fulton Celebration (PR 268) [1 folder]
      Karp, Marilyn & Ivan (PR 279) [2 folders]
      Landauer (PR 31) [18 folders]
      Lighthouse Print & Photograph Collection (PR 38) [1 folder]
      McCullough, Hall Park–Graphic Arts (PR 22) [1 folder]
      [Naval History Society]–Maritime History Collection (PR 100) [1 folder]
      Mark David Olds WWII Collection (PR 287) [1 folder]
      Pagliaro (PR 282) [1 folder]
      Paul Gillespie Collection of New York World's Fair Materials (PR 283) [1 folder]
      Portrait File (PR 52) [3 folders]
      Harry Rosen El Borracho Collection (PR 308) [1 folder]
    - Mixed Material Collections S-W (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 3)
      Schafler Graphic Collection (PR 331) [1 folder]
      Subject File (PR 68) [1 folder]
      Theatrical Portrait File (PR 104) [2 folders]
      Vanderbilt House and Collection (PR 173) [1 folder]
      Winston Weisman Architectural Photographs (PR 73) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections A-Be (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 3)
      Agassiz Association (PR 167) [1 folder]
      John Albok Collection (PR 01) [3 folders]
      Alexander Alland Collection (PR 110) [1 folder]
      Anaconda Smelter Photo Collection (PR 222) [1 folder]
      Armbruster Collection (PR 81) [1 folder]
      Bill Aron Collection (PR 192) [1 folder]
      Jessie Tarbox Beals (PR 04) [11 folders]
    - Photo Collections Bi-Car (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 4)
      Billboard Collection (PR 5) [3 folders]
      Blackstone-Shelbourne Studio Portrait Collection aka Jacobs (PR 114) [1 folder]
      Herman Blumenthal Collection (PR 119) [1 folder]
      Bracklow Collection (PR 08) [8 folders]
      George Bradley Civil War photos (PR 218) [1 folder]
      Brady Studio Portrait Collection (PR 85) [1 folder]
      David Brandin Photo Collection (PR 273) [1 folder]
      Margaret Brown Dutch Houses (PR 118) [1 folder]
      Louise Browne Photograph Collection (PR 171) [1 folder]
      Browning Photograph Collection (PR 09) [3 folders]
      Carte de Visite Photograph File (PR 11) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections Cas-Dod (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 5)
      Cased Image Collection (PR 12) [5 folders]
      Lucius H. Cathan Collection (PR 132) [1 folder]
      Cathedral Church of St. John the Divine - Hervey Collection (PR 13) [1 folder]
      Arthur D. Chapman Photos (PR 15) [1 folder]
      H. M. Chester Photos (PR 131) [1 folder]
      Civil War Photographs ( PR 164) [1 folder]
      Ernst Cohen Photos (PR 280) [1 folder]
      Con Edison Photograph Collection (DISPERSED to other collections) [2 folders]
      Costume Ball Collection (PR 223) [1 folder]
      Cotterell Negative Collection (nitrates) (PR 238) [1 folder]
      Frank W. Crane Collection (PR 128) [1 folder]
      Cross and Brown Architectural Photos (PR 111) [2 folders]
      Bill Cunningham Photos (PR 307) [1 folders]
      Bruce Davidson Photos (PR 89) [1 folder]
      DeGroot Family Photos (PR 120) [1 folder]
      Dept. of Docks and Ferries Photos (PR 262) [1 folder]
      George C. Dodd Photos (PR 168) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections Dog-Gor (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 6)
      Burhan Dogancy Photos (PR 183) [1 folder]
      Asher B. Durand Negative Collection (PR 165) [1 folder]
      Wilberforce Eames Negative Collection (PR 112) [1 folder]
      Early American West Photos (PR 266) [1 folder]
      Edouart Silhouette Photo Collection (PR 101) [1 folder]
      Equitable Building Fire Photos (PR 330) [1 folder]
      Andreas Feininger Photo Collection (PR 207) [3 folders]
      Fifth Avenue Coach Company Photos (PR 18) [2 folders]
      Rhoda Galyn Photos (PR 197) [1 folder]
      Robert Gambee Photos (PR 198) [1 folder]
      Arnold Genthe Photos (PR 19) [6 folders]
      Michael George Photos (PR 199) [1 folder]
      George Washington Bridge Construction Photos (PR 137) [1 folder]
      Ray Germann Collection (PR 311) [1 folder]
      Gettysburg War Memorials Photos (PR 214) [1 folder]
      Goodwill Delegation Collection (PR 124) [1 folder]
      Eugene Gordon (PR 248) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections Got-Ha (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 7)
      Bernard Gotfryd (PR 276) [4 folders]
      William Grabowski (PR 321) [1 folder]
      Norvin Green Elevated Railroad Photos (PR 23) [1 folder]
      Arthur Grumbine Photos (PR 97) [1 folder]
      George P. Hall Photos (PR 24) [3 folders]
      Lathrop and Mabel Urner Harper Photos (PR 121) [1 folder]
      Hassler Photographs (PR 83) [3 folders]
      Alexander Hatos Photos (PR 48) [1 folder]
      Havemeyer/de Loosey Family Photos (PR 130) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections He-Ken (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 8)
      Mattie Hewitt and Richard Smith Photos (PR 26) [5 folders]
      Chester Higgins Photos (PR 176) [1 folder]
      Eugene Higgins House Photos (PR 140) [1 folder]
      Charles Gilbert Hines Photos (PR 82) [4 folders]
      Lewis Hine "Newsies" Photos of Newsboys (PR 188) [2 folders]
      Henry B. Hoffman Photos (PR 236) [1 folder]
      Kim Hoffman Photos (PR 77) [1 folder]
      Holland Society Photos of Cortelyou and Bergen Houses (PR 328) [1 folder]
      Raymond Hood Photos (PR 148) [1 folder]
      Howe Family Photos (PR 292) [1 folder]
      Morris Huberland Photos (PR 194) [1 folder]
      Daniel Huntington Study Portraits (PR 256) [1 folder]
      Julian Hyman Photos (PR 320) [1 folder]
      Charles G. Johnson Photos (PR 172) [1 folder]
      J.S. Johnston Photos (PR 219) [1 folder]
      Imperial Portrait Photo File (PR 210) [1 folder]
      Frank M. Ingalls Photos (PR 28) [1 folder]
      Jennings Photo (PR 135) [1 folder]
      Kabakov Photos (PR 278) [1 folder]
      Kalinsky- empty folder marked "see N-YHS RG21 Box 339"
      Charles S. Kelly Photos (PR 260) [1 folder]
      Frederick Kelly Photos (PR 246) [1 folder]
      Roy Kemp (rejected photos) [1 folder]
      William Sargent Kendall (PR 156) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections Ke-N (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 9)
      Sidney Kerner Photos (PR 193) [1 folder]
      Theron W. Kilmer Portraits (PR 30) [1 folder]
      Landmarks (PR 310) [1 folder]
      Richard Hoe Lawrence Photos (PR 32) [1 folder]
      Rebecca Lepkoff Photos (PR 295) [1 folder]
      Robert M. Lester Photos (PR 215) [1 folder]
      Edwin Levick Studio Photos (PR 34) [1 folder]
      Herman Liberman Photos (PR 36) [1 folder]
      William E. Light Photos (PR 37) [1 folder]
      Livingston Family Photos (PR 138) [1 folder]
      Carl Lobozza Photos (PR 269) [1 folder]
      Lower East Side Photos (PR 251) [1 folder]
      Pirie MacDonald Portraits (PR 39) [2 folders]
      Jack Margolin (PR 316) [1 folder]
      Edwin Martin (PR 96) [1 folder]
      Fred McDaragh (No PR) [1 folder]
      Burr McIntosh (PR 41) [3 folders]
      McLaughlin Air Service Photos (PR 43) [1 folder]
      Ron Meisel Photos (PR 377) [1 folder]
      Meserve Historical Portraits (PR 231) [1 folder]
      Metropolitan Street Railway Photos (PR 177) [1 folder]
      Metz/Greene Family Collection (PR 133) [1 folder]
      William Meyers (No PR) [1 folder]
      Lida Moser Photos (PR 123) [1 folder]
      George Murdock Steamboat Photos (PR 44) [2 folders]
      Eadweard Muybridge Photos (PR 205) [1 folder]
      George Nash Photos (PR 239) [1 folder]
      New York City Photographic Slides (PR 278) [1 folder]
      New York City Public Works Construction Photos (PR 302) [1 folder]
      New York Subway Construction Negatives (PR 232) [1 folder]
      N-YHS Field Exploration Committee (PR 240) [1 folder]
      New York Inside Out (No PR) [3 folders]
    - Photo Collections O-Rom (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 10)
      Ruth Orkin Photo Collection (PR 190) [1 folder]
      Pach Brothers Portraits (PR 84) [5 folders]
      Packard Junior College Photos (PR 109) [1 folder]
      Ferdinand Pecora Collection (PR 150) [1 folder]
      Photographer File (PR 50) [7 folders]
      Harris Pierce Photos (PR 270) [1 folder]
      Richard Pieronek Slides (PR 327) [1 folder]
      James T. Powers and Rachel Booth Photos (PR 105) [1 folder]
      Victor Prevost Photos (PR 56) [3 folders]
      Larry Racioppo Photos (PR 208) [1 folder]
      Ramppen Family Photos (PR 136) [1 folder]
      Ransom Collection (PR 237) [1 folder]
      Raven Poetry Circle Collection (PR 108) [1 folder]
      William F. Reeves Elevated Railroad Photos (PR 154) [2 folders]
      Rettinger Glass Plate Negatives (PR 174) [1 folder]
      Jacob Riis Reference Photo Collection (PR 59) [2 folders]
      William J. Roege Photos (PR 181) [1 folder]
      John Rogers Photos (PR 122) [1 folder]
      James Romeo Photos (PR 180) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections Ros-Su (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 11)
      Mel Rosenthal Photo Collection (PR 90) [1 folder]
      Harold Roth Photos (PR 195) [1 folder]
      June Rovenger (PR 291) [1 folder]
      David Sagarin Photos (PR 200) [1 folder]
      Salmagundi Club Photos (PR 182) [1 folder]
      Savastano Hell's Kitchen Photos (PR 178) [1 folder]
      Joseph Scanlon Steamboat Photos (PR 60) [1 folder]
      Carl W. Schmidt Jr. Photos (PR 275) [1 folder]
      Kenneth Siegel Photos (PR 298) [1 folder]
      Irwin Silver Photos (PR 209) [1 folder]
      S.S. Silver Company Collection (PR 61) [1 folder]
      Caleb Smith Photos (PR 253) [1 folder]
      James Reuel Smith Springs and Wells Photos (PR 62) [1 folder]
      Frederick H. Smyth Fire Photos (PR 63) [1 folder]
      Stephen Somerstein Photos (PR 314) [1 folder]
      Michael Sonnenfeldt Photos (PR 305) [1 folder]
      South Side Sportsmen's Club of Long Island (PR 211) [1 folder]
      Jerry Spagnoli Photos (PR 157) [1 folder]
      Jan Staller (PR 201) [1 folder]
      Stella Snead Photos (PR 185) [1 folder]
      Steinway and Sons Photos (PR 166) [1 folder]
      Stereograph File (PR 65) [2 folders]
      Henry A. Stimson Family Photos (PR 155) [1 folder]
      Erica Stone Photos (PR 267) [1 folder]
      Stonebridge Collection (PR 66) [4 folders]
      Helen Stummer Photos (PR 235) [1 folder]
      Subway Construction Photos (PR 69) [5 folders]
    - Photo Collections Sy-Woo (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 12)
      Jack Sydow Collection (PR 289) [1 folder]
      Harry Tarzian Photos (PR 255) [1 folder]
      Thomas Air Views (PR 106) [1 folder]
      Emma Thursby Photos (PR 126) [1 folder]
      Daniel F. Teimann Family Photos (PR 134) [1 folder]
      H.N. Tiemann and Co. Photos (PR 129) [1 folder]
      Philip Trager ( PR 202) [1 folder]
      Transparency FIle (PR 70) [2 folders]
      John Judson Trappan Photos (PR 71) [1 folder]
      Doris Ulmann Photos (PR 72) [5 folders]
      United Nations Construction Photos (PR 91) [1 folder]
      U.S. Army Supply Base Construction Photos (PR 249) [1 folder]
      Camilo Jose Vergara (PR 286) [1 folder]
      John J. Vrooman Photos (PR 252) [1 folder]
      Harvey Wang Photos (PR 175) [1 folder]
      War of the Rebellion Albums (PR 88) [1 folder]
      Watkins, Carleton (No PR) [1 folder]
      James Watson Webb Jr. Collection (PR 318) [1 folder]
      Arthur Weindorf Collection (PR 127) [1 folder]
      Norman Weisberg Collection (PR 179) [1 folder]
      Wells Family Photos (PR 139) [1 folder]
      Wenzel Collection (PR 74) [1 folder]
      Westchester County Historical Pageant Photos (PR 184) [1 folder]
      Lewis White Photos (PR 196) [1 folder]
      Orrin Sage Wightman Collection (PR 94) [1 folder]
      Harry Wilks Photos (PR 186) [1 folder]
      William Winters' Shaker Community Photos (PR 206) [1 folder]
      Winkowski (No PR) [1 folder]
      Woolworth Building Photos (PR 187) [1 folder]
    - Photo Collections Wor-Y (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 13)
      World Financial Center Photos (PR 191) [1 folder]
      World Trade Center Photos (PR 169) [4 folders]
      World War II Photos (PR 76) [1 folders]
      Wright Photos (PR 203) [1 folder]
      Claire Yaffa Photos (PR 290 and PR 299) [2 folders]
    - Architecture Collections A-M (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 13)
      Michael Arad 9/11 Memorial (PR 422) [1 folder]
      Architects and Engineers (PR 03) [1 folder]
      Adler and Neilson Iron Works Drawings (PR 415) [1 folder]
      Clarke and Rapuano Landscape Architecture (PR 80) [1 folder]
      Donnelly Architectural Sculpture (PR 233) [1 folder]
      A.J. Davis Drawings (PR 16 ) [9 folders]
      James W. Martens (PR 113) [1 folder]
      John McComb (PR 40) [10 folders]
    - Architecture Collections N-W (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 14)
      Siebrand Niewenhous Architectural Specs (PR 93) [2 folders]
      Calvin Pollard Architectural Drawings (PR 51) [1 folder]
      George B. Post Collection (PR 53) [6 folders]
      John Rink Central Park Drawing- in Arch & Eng File (PR 03) [1 folder]
      Stanley R. Rosenberg Architectural Records (PR 254) [1 folder]
      Emery Roth Architectural Prints (PR 170) [1 folder]
      Thomas Sopolsky and Slobodien Collection (PR 439) [1 folder]
      John B. Snook Architectural Records (PR 64) [4 folders]
      Warren & Wetmore- in Arch and Eng. File (PR 03) [1 folder]
    - Print Collections A-Bou (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 14)
      American Art Union Prints (PR 159) [2 folders]
      Alexander Anderson Prints (PR 216) [1 folder]
      Audubon Print Collection (PR 162) [1 folder]
      John Bachman (PR 353) [1 folder]
      James Carroll Beckwith Study Collection (PR 158) [1 folder]
      William James Bennett Collection (PR 220) [1 folder]
      William Birch (No PR) [1 folder]
      Bookplate File (PR 06) [2 folders]
      Mortimer Bourne Drypoint Collection (PR 226) [1 folder]
    - Print Collections Boy-H (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 15)
      James Boyd Etchings (PR 07) [1 folder]
      Bryan Gallery of Christian Art (PR 143) [1 folder]
      Caricatures and Cartoons (PR 10) [2 folders]
      Clipper Ship Cards (PR 116) [2 folders]
      Isaccher Cozzens Collections (PR 145) [1 folder]
      Currier and Ives Prints (PR 230) [1 folder]
      Homer C. Davenport Caricatures (PR 125) [1 folder]
      Detroit Publishing Company (PR 272) [1 folder]
      John Ward Dunsmore (No PR) [1 folder]
      Asher B. Durand Prints (PR 221) [1 folder]
      Louis Durr Collection (PR 142) [1 folder]
      European Print File (PR 151) [1 folder]
      Feinstein Collection (PR 300) [1 folder]
      Graphic Arts File (PR 22) [1 folder]
      Henry O. Havemeyer Portraits of American Statesmen (PR 25) [1 folder]
      Hershkowitz Collection of Civil War Illustrations (PR 263) [1 folder]
      John Hill Prints (PR 217) [1 folder]
      Samuel Hollyer's Old New York Views (PR 86) [1 folder]
      James Hazen Hyde (PR 27) [2 folders]
    - Print Collections I-Postcard (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 16)
      Anthony Imbert Prints (PR 225) [1 folder]
      Kane-Greenberg Cigar Labels (PR 242) [1 folder]
      Steven Katz (No PR) [1 folder]
      Keppler Cartoon Collection (PR 29) [1 folder]
      James King Print Collection (PR 227) [1 folder]
      Landauer Reference and Writing Collection (PR 149) [2 folders]
      LeBoeuf Collection (PR 33) [1 folder]
      Charles M. Lefferts Military Uniforms (PR 99) [1 folder]
      Liberman Collection of Wall Street Prints (PR 35) [1 folder]
      Marco Luccio Drypoint Prints (PR 409) [1 folder]
      Reginald Marsh (PR 341) [1 folder]
      Peter Maverick Prints (PR 224) [1 folder]
      McGuigan Collection of Chapman Etchings (PR 265) [1 folder]
      Manhattan Graphics Center 9/11 prints (PR 257) [1 folder]
      William Rickaby Miller Study Collection (PR 152) [1 folder]
      NY State Legislature Portrait Prints (PR 213) [1 folder]
      Ogden Collection (PR 147) [1 folder]
      Alfred Olcott Hudson River Steamboat (PR 98) [1 folder]
      Irving S. Olds Collection (PR 47) [1 folder]
      Ottman Collection (PR 281) [2 folders]
      Paper Doll Collection (PR 161) [1 folder]
      Patriotic Envelopes (PR 117) [1 folder]
      Harry T. Peters Collection (PR 49) [3 folders]
      Pictorial Letter Sheet Collection (PR 144) [1 folder]
      Playing Cards and Games Collection (PR 115) [5 folders]
      Postcard File (PR 54) [1 folder]
    - Print Collections Poster-Y (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 17)
      Poster File (PR 055) [1 folder]
      Printing Plate File–Alexander Anderson woodblocks (PR 057) [1 folder]
      Printing Plate File (PR 057) [1 folder]
      Printmaker File (PR 058) [5 folders]
      Prized Prints (NO PR) [2 folders]
      Luman Reed NY Gallery of Fine Arts (PR 141) [1 folder]
      Jacques Reich Portrait Prints (PR 102) [1 folder]
      Saint-Memin Print Collection (PR 226) [1 folder]
      Lockwood Sanford Wood Engraving Proof Books (PR 247) [1 folder]
      Society of Iconophiles Prints (PR 160) [1 folder]
      Strobridge Poster Collection (PR 67) [2 folders]
      Ira Unschuld Print Club of NY Collection (PR 388) [1 folder]
      Vache Family Embroidery Pattern Collection (PR 163) [1 folder]
      Sidney Voice Collection of Cigar Bands (PR 241) [1 folder]
      Wattman Bookmark Collection (PR 204) [1 folder]
      WPA Prints Collection (PR 345) [1 folder]
      Charles Lennox Wright Collection (PR 75) [1 folder]
      George Henry Yewell Collection (PR 153) [1 folder]
    - Cass Gilbert Collection (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 18)
      Cass Gilbert (PR 21) [24 folders]
    - McKim, Mead and White Collection (Offsite-box PPAC Collection Files 19)
      McKim, Mead and White (PR 42) [27 folders]
- Series IX. Conservation, 1989-2004; 9.42 Linear feet
  The series includes three principal sets of records from the library's conservation lab. First are the lab's files of outgoing loans and in-house exhibitions from 1989 to 2005. Second are the files (1990-1993) of Associate Librarian for Preservation Duane Watson and those of his colleague, Stacks Manager Christine Seeto. Finally, there are records of a daguerreotype (cased images) conservation survey from 1992-1993.
  The outgoing loan files are generally fairly slender, with uneven content. Many include conservation treatment notes, but others include just the record of the approved loan or general correspondence about the loans. Some post-2000 files include color slides of the loaned objects. In-house exhibition files tend to be more extensive, reflecting the broader involvement of the lab with these activities. These exhibition files commonly include not only condition and treatment reports, but also basic information about the objects in relation to the exhibition, including labels, checklists, display logistics, etc. The loan and exhibition files include folder lists at the front of each box.
  The Watson records are generally of a more administrative and broader nature, and less focused on individual objects. Watson's records include budgets, survey results, performance statistics, internal memos, conservation reference material, grants, and grant project activities. Seeto's records are concerned with stack surveys, movements of material within the stacks and other such logistical matters.
  Files on conservation matters, including grants, projects, preservation microfilming, etc. can be found in the above series as well, especially Series IV. Librarian & Curatorial Files and Series VIII. Print Room.
  Outgoing loans and exhibition files are presented first. They are in their original folders and original order, which is chronological. These are followed by a carton of detailed records of a daguerreotype survey. Watson's and Seeto's records close the series. Watson's files are in their original folders and original order, which is alphabetical by subject. Seeto's files are also in their original folders and original order, which seems to have no particular arrangement.
  Aside from a bindery that operated from 1929 until about 1960, N-YHS had no in-house conservation unit until the mid-1980s when it began to build such a staff, initially for the museum. Professional conservators arrived in the library when paper and book conservation labs were opened in early 1989. In 1990, Duane Watson was hired as Associate Librarian for Preservation, a position he held until he left N-YHS in early 1993. In this position, Watson was responsible for overseeing object-level conservation efforts for the library and the management of the collection in the stacks. This latter responsibility was carried out in the early 1990s principally by Stacks Manager Christine Seeto. Down to the present (2016), N-YHS's library has continued to maintain a conservation lab, headed since the mid-1990s by chief conservator, Alan Balicki. Among the conservation staff's many responsibilities has been the assessment of outgoing loans of objects (e.g., conditions of objects, proper housing, conditions at the borrower site) and preparation of objects for in-house exhibitions.
  - Outgoing Loan Files (1 of 2 boxes), 1989-1999 (Offsite-box 285, Folder 1-103)
  - Outgoing Loan Files (2 of 2 boxes), 2000-2004 (Offsite-box 286, Folder 1-73)
  - Exhibition Files (1 of 3 boxes), 1991-1998 (Offsite-box 287, Folder 1-64)
  - Exhibition Files (2 of 3 boxes), 1999-2001 (Offsite-box 288, Folder 1-47)
  - Exhibition Files (3 of 3 boxes), 2002-2005 (Offsite-box 289, Folder 1-57)
  - Daguerreotype (Cased Images) Conservation Survey Cards (RESTRICTED), 1992-1993 (Offsite-box 290, Cards -)
    Because of the fragile condition of these records, they may be used only by advance appointment with the Manuscripts Reference Librarian and in consultation with the library's conservator.
  - Duane Watson Files (1 of 3 boxes), 1990-1992 (Offsite-box 291, Folder 1-63)
    Includes subject files A-G including, among other subjects, budget/financial, preservation consultant reports (including results of a statistical survey by Richard Frieder of the New York State and City Collection), conservation plans, permanent collections gallery re-installation planning, floor plans, grants.
  - Duane Watson Files (2 of 3 boxes), 1990-1992 (Offsite-box 292, Folder 1-61)
    Includes subject files G-R including, among other subjects, grants, OPAC/cataloging statistics, staff memos/monthly status reports (under Personnel), RLG projects.
  - Duane Watson Files (3 of 3 boxes), 1990-1992 (Offsite-box 293, Folder 1-15)
    Includes subject files R-W including, among other subjects, RLG projects (e.g. preservation microfilming), wood block conservation.
  - Christine Seeto Files (65 folders), 1990-1993 (Offsite-box 132, Folder 1-66)
    Includes files on collection surveys, inventories, locations and relocations in the stacks, stack maps, and other stacks/collection management matters.
- Series X. Public Service (RESTRICTED IN PART), 1829-2011; 35.58 Linear feet
  The Public Service series is organized in the following subseries:
  Subseries X.A. Visitor Sign-in Registers and Related Material (1829-2010)
  Subseries X.B. Reading Room Records (1949-2007)
  Subseries X.C. Print Room Public Service Records (1942-2008)